David Ennis

UX & UI Web Designer

Cumming, GA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/David-Ennis/67d71cb2ea1aafbc

A User Experience (UX) & User Interface Designer experienced in working with small businesses, mediumsized companies, and corporate Telecoms. Wireframes and design of responsive web applications using Adobe Suite, Sketch, Axure RP, HTML5, and CSS3. A self-starter that is a team-player and driven to provide branded products and results that exceed expectations.

Willing to relocate to: Nashville, TN

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Designer

HP - Alpharetta, GA - April 2016 to Present

Design mobile and desktop applications for Aurasma, HP's Augmented Reality software.

Interpret and translate user research data and business requirements into intuituve experiences.

Create rapid prototypes of mobile applications integrating augmented reality into other HP applications as well as for other vendors.

DIRECTOR OF WEB & GRAPHIC DESIGN

Grace Fellowship of South Forsyth - Cumming, GA - 2005 to Present

Responsibilities

- Create the branding and logos of the organization and its ministries
- Design web and print advertisements for scheduled events & opportunities
- Develop and maintain the organization's responsive website using WordPress and Genesis
- Manage a volunteer team responsible for content, developing functionality, and maintenance Implement Asana as the organization's project management tool for internal ministries

UX & WEB DESIGNER

Verizon Wireless - Alpharetta, GA - 2009 to 2015

Responsibilities

- Collaborated with the Revenue Team to create high-resolution wire frames of applications that manage catalog content and revenue data for the business, vendors, and resellers
- Documented user stories and screen ows for user personas/roles and their tasks
- Designed universal create, read, update, and delete design patterns for various data and catalog content types
- Created screen mock-ups of the mobile Verizon Wireless Media Store
- Organized and managed the team's SharePoint site used for resource management, project status, documentation storage, attendance, and communication
- Developed training presentations for new employees about supported applications

UX & WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

Alltel - Alpharetta, GA - 2003 to 2009

Responsibilities

- Translated and documented business and user requirements into application prototypes
- Developed rich Internet applications to manage business processes and data
- Designed website templates that comply with corporate style guides
- Developed website style guides and applied the styles to JSP pages
- Defined site maps and process ows for various user pro les and buyer types
- Created relational database structures for web applications

WEB DESIGNER

BELLSOUTH TECHNOLOGIES GROUP - Atlanta, GA - 1999 to 2002

Responsibilities

- Defined site flows and maps of Internet sites, intranets, and applications
- · Analyzed business objectives, proposed solutions, and defined project requirements
- Designed user interfaces that complied with the corporate style guide
- Developed HTML prototypes for usability studies and business approval
- Analyzed user testing and focus group research and developed solutions

ADVERTISING DIRECTOR

Medical Doctor Associates - Norcross, GA - 1995 to 1999

Responsibilities

- Designed corporate identities and branding for a family of companies
- Produced marketing materials: ads, brochures, direct mail, trade show exhibits, etc.
- · Defined goals and architected content for websites within existing marketing structures
- · Selected appropriate vendors and developed content for web marketing campaigns
- Designed and optimized graphics, photographs, and animations

EDUCATION

BFA in Electronic Arts

Atlanta College of Art - Atlanta, GA 1990 to 1994

SKILLS

HTML (10+ years), CSS (10+ years), Wire framing (10+ years), Photoshop (10+ years), Illustrator (10+ years), Dreamweaver (10+ years), InDesign (10+ years), Sketch (Less than 1 year), Axure (5 years)

LINKS

http://www.guiroo.com

AWARDS

Support Employee of The Year

1997

Lead company and its sister companies through a corporate rebranding.

Bellsouth Target Award

2001

Designed the offical site of the Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial that was to reveal the selected memorial design and collect funds and donations for its completion.

Nielsen Norman Group 2002 Best Corporate Intranets

2002

Participated in the effort of redesigning the Bellsouth Corporate Intranet that was voted to be one of the year's best by NN/G.